Stanislav Starishko

Glasgow, UK, G72 8PG | WhatsApp/Tel: 07387914778 | Email: starishko.s@gmail.com

Web: https://github.com/StanStarishko/Portfolio | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/starishko/

Permit: Category B | Legally authorized to work in the UK

Personal Statement:

Motivated results-driven professional with years of experience, recognised for assessing operational needs, and developing solutions to save costs, improve revenues and drive customer satisfaction. Resourceful, well-organised with excellent leadership and team-building record. Passionate Developer with experience in data accuracy, management. Independent problem-solver focused on customer service, product development. Works well under tight deadlines. Since April 2023, had academically advancing my skills in Python, Java, Agile, Cyber Resilience, APIs. Currently, actively seek new challenges in the role of a Software Engineer

Technical Skills:

- Programming Languages: 1C (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, and SalesForce), T-SQL, Java (Collections, Lambda Expressions), Python (Flask, Pandas, NumPy, Lambda Expressions), JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Turbo Pascal, Delphi, C, C++
- Development Tools & Environments: Delivering complex (ERP) enterprise level systems, Writing secure and high-quality code, Full Life Cycle and Decisions Architecture, Object-Oriented (OOP), Modular Programming, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), SOLID, QA MT/AT, Unit Testing, Test Driven Development (TDD), BDD, Design of architecture IT products, services and solutions, AWS, Lambda, S3, APIs, Jira, Trello, Data and system analyst
- Databases: MSSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall, and Time, Team, Product, Project, and Crisis Management

Key Skills:

- Enthusiastic up for challenge
- Analytical and Outside The Box Thinking
 Crisis Resolution
- Excellent Team Collaboration
- Passionate about software
- Attention to Detail
- Team Productivity Enhancement
- Business Process Understanding
- Process Modernization

Work History:

Glasgow Film Theatre, UK

08/2023 - Current

Volunteer-Customer Assistant

- Provided advice and assistance to clients, checked tickets, cleaned up after the show
- Reached English skills from A1 to B1 Level

EVOS Good Food, Uzbekistan

09/2021 - 02/2022

Director of Digital Transformation

- Initiated the delivery of ERP systems, boosting accounting and finance productivity by 30%
- Contributed to innovative solutions implementation of timekeeping facial recognition by Hik-Vision into HRsystem, ERP enhancing HR processes by 80% within 2.5 months
- Introduced steps to halt technological debt growth within two months

Freelance, Ukraine

11/2019 - 08/2021

Software Engineer

• Developed software modules improved the speed of financial reporting by 25% by 1C (akin to Java, Python, C#, C/C++, Dynamics, and SalesForce)

EVA Retail, Ukraine

10/2018 - 11/2019

Head of the Software Department

- Introduced adoption of innovative methodologies, including SBS feedback, Agile, Scrum, CorpScrum, Prince2, hybrid Waterfall (PMBOK) approach, resulting in 20% boost in team productivity
- Successfully managed over 10 long-term projects (each 1-3 years), one of key ones is payment calendar
- executed more than 20 short-term projects (each up to 6 months) to conclusion, consistently meeting all deadlines
- Developed strategy plan to redeveloped support software for 900+ retail outlets, 3500+ users, achieving an efficiency improvement of 10%

- Developed, rolled-out of complex enterprise-level systems (ERP), resulting in 10% uplift in productivity for accounting, finance departments
- Deployed strategic framework successfully stopped growth of company's technological debt within 4 month

Alef and Other Corporations, Ukraine

03/2014 - 10/2018

Re-entry from Junior 1C8 Developer to Head of Software Department

- Solved problems in 280 1C databases on MSSQL, reduced update time by 98%, from 2.5 months to 3-5 days
- Spearheaded transformative initiative skyrocketed support team's efficiency by an impressive 80%
- Overcame seemed insurmountable challenges within remarkable 2 weeks, and outpaced outsourcing projections set for 8 month timeframe
- Reduction of exchange time from 8-14 hours to 2-5 minutes by deployed high-speed synchronization system for 1C (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, and SalesForce), with Office Tools
- Orchestrated the seamless execution of a comprehensive automation plan for manufacturing within an ambitious 10-month timeline, beginning from scratch

Company Adeon Franchising 1C, Ukraine Co-owner/CEO

02/2007 - 03/2014

• Successfully delivered 12+ long-term projects within specified timelines, ranging from 8 to 18 months, utilising 1C (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, and SalesForce), T-SQL, MSSQL

Retail and Logistic Companies, Ukraine

10/1991 - 02/2007

Software Developer

- In 2003, rapid effectively, for one month, retrained to 1C developer (akin to Java, Python, C#, C/C++, Dynamics, and SalesForce)
- Championed software development excellence for over a decade from 1991 to 2003, demonstrating proficiency in Turbo Pascal, Delphi, C, C++

Education and Training:

PDA Cyber Resilience	SCQF8	Code Division, futureCoders	UK	11/2023 - 03/2024
Cyber Engineers	CyberOps Associate	Cisco Networking Academy	UK	11/2023 - 03/2024
PDA Software Development	SCQF7	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	08/2023 - 11/2023
NPA Software Development	SCQF6	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	04/2023 - 07/2023
NQ Access to Business Administration, Accounting and IT	SCQF4	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	01/2023 - 06/2023
Python	Fundamental	DataCamp	USA	11/2022 - 03/2023
New strategic thinking. Selection Management	Advanced	EVA Academy, Arkadiy Tsuker	Ukraine	05/2019 - 05/2019
Project Management by Agile, Scrum and Kanban	Advanced	EVA Academy	Ukraine	11/2018 - 04/2019
Corporate course of business changes and transformation	МВА	Institute of Adizes, Ukrainian Office	USA	02/2018 - 09/2018
Programming for Computing Devices and Automated Systems	BTEC, SCQF7	Automation and Telemechan College	Ukraine	09/1990 - 03/1993

Languages: English - Intermediate, Ukrainian – Native, Russian - Native

Hobbies & Interests: Traveling, exploring new technologies, personal development